[音乐]
[MUSIC]
&GT；&GT；道格拉斯：让我们谈谈责任。
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Let's talk about responsibility.
当你编程时，你对谁负责？
Who are you responsible to when you're programming?
这就是我的答案
Well this is my answer,
这就是我认为我在编写代码时应该对其负责的人。
this is who I think I am responsible to when I'm writing code.
我的首要责任是对人民。
My number one responsibility is to The People.
给那些不得不用我的软件的可怜的混蛋。
To the poor bastards who have to use my software.
我想为他们工作得很好，我不想让他们沮丧，
I want to work really well for them, I don't want to frustrate them,
我不想混淆他们，我不想伤害他们，
I don't want to confuse them, I don't want to hurt them,
我不想让他们走向毁灭，我想给他们尽可能最好的体验，
I don't want to lead them to ruin, I want to give them the best experience possible,
我想尽我所能让他们的生活变得更好。
I want to make their lives better to the extent that I can.
我们想象在软件行业，我们正在让世界变得更美好
We imagine in the software industry that we're making the world a better place
尽管有所有明显的相反证据，
despite all the obvious evidence to the contrary,
我们真的很想相信这一点，但我们至少应该试着让它成为现实
we'd really want to believe that but we should at least try to make it true for
正在使用我们的东西的人，因为他们正在使用它。
the people who are using our stuff as they're using it.
我们至少应该这么做。
We should at least do that.
我见过这样的团队，他们蔑视他们的用户，他们讨厌他们的用户，
I've seen teams where they have contempt for their users, they hate their users,
用户总是抱怨，他们不知道如何使用他们的东西，
the user's always complaining, they don't understand how to use their stuff,
他们不欣赏我们的天才，他们愚蠢，他们是可怕的人，
they don't appreciate our genius, they're stupid, they're awful people,
恨他们，我认为这是完全有毒的，这是不可原谅的。
hate them, which I think is totally toxic, that it's inexcusable.
我们永远不应该那样想。
We should never be thinking like that.
我们所做的一切都应该为人类服务。
Everything that we do should be in service to humanity.
第二，团队。
Number two, The team.
我想写出我能写的最好的代码，最清晰，最好的，
I want to be writing the best code that I can, the clearest, best,
良好的文档，易于理解，良好的代码，因为
well documented, easy to understand, good code because
我将与之合作的其他人将不得不接受该代码
other people who I'm gonna be working with are gonna have to take that code and
让它变得更好，我不想让他们失败，
make it better and I don't want to be setting them up for failure,
我不想让他们失望，我不想让他们的生活更糟，
I don't want to be frustrating them, I don't want to be making their lives worse,
我想让他们的生活变得更好，我希望每个人都有好的代码
I want to make their lives better, I want good code for everybody and
我希望他们也能这样做，这样编程就可以
I expect them to do the same so programming can be
一个人的活动，但通常我们试图做的事情，这是如此复杂。
a solo activity but generally we're trying to do stuff which is so complicated.
我们试着这么快做。
We're trying to do it so quickly.
我们几乎每时每刻都在团队合作，有时甚至是大团队。
We're working in teams almost all the time and sometimes big teams.
在大量的文学作品中，有一个想法就是用单一的声音写作。
And in large literary efforts, there's this idea of writing with a single voice.
就像你在写一本百科全书，或者
Like if you're writing an encyclopedia, or
如果你有几个作家在写一本书，或者你在写一本杂志，或者
if your a couple of authors writing a book, or if you're writing a magazine, or
还有一件事，我们有很多作家在同一个项目上工作。
some other thing we've got lots of writers working on the same project.
他们都试图用同样的声音写作。
They're all trying to write in the same voice.
这不会干扰
And that doesn't interfere at
所有这些都需要能够表达好的想法并清楚地表达出来。
all with being able to express good ideas and presenting it clearly.
我认为我们也需要在编写软件时做到这一点，所以
And I think we need to be doing that in writing software too, so
我希望我们都用同样的声音写作
I want us to be writing all in the same voice and
这个声音是有史以来最聪明、最专业的程序员。
that voice is the smartest most professional programmer who's ever lived.
我希望团队中的每个人都能写到那个水平。
I want everybody on the team to be writing up to that level.
我不希望任何人因为他们认为他们需要
I don't want anybody dumbing it down because they think they need to
通过省略分号来表达自己。
express themselves by leaving out the semicolons.
我希望每个人都写得很好。
I want everybody to be writing really well.
然后是第三个，管理。
Then number three, Management.
如果他们要求，而且有意义，好的，我们也会这样做。
If they ask for it and it makes sense, okay we'll do that too.
现在一些经理可能会说，哇，这一分钟，我们应该在
Now some managers might be saying, woh, what a minute, we're supposed to be in
在这里充电，难道我们不应该是第一名吗？我不这么认为。
charge here, shouldn't we be number one and I don't think so.
我认为三号是适合他们的地方。
I think number three is the right place for them.
如果你看看首席执行官做什么，他们最重要的职责之一
If you look at what a CEO does one of their most important responsibilities
就是帮助公司提高警惕。
is to help the company look out.
公司有一种趋势，特别是当他们变得更大的时候
There's a tendency in the company especially as they get bigger
一切都集中在里面。
that everything is focused inside.
有争夺资源、关注和晋升的竞争
There's competition for resources and attention and promotion and
所有这些东西，你往往会忘记客户和
all of that stuff, and you tend to forget about the customer and
你可以忘记，你会倾向于忘记市场和所有这些
you can forget the and you tend to forget about the marketplace and all these really
实际上比内心发生的事情更重要的事情
things that are actually much more important than what's going on inside and
CEO的部分职责是提醒公司这一点
part of the CEO's role is to remind the company of that and
你看首席执行官总是说要做客户，要以客户为中心
you see CEO's always saying things like be the customer and be customer focused and
所有这些东西就是这一切的意义所在。
all that stuff that's what that's all about.
这与我所说的非常一致
And that's very compatible with what I'm what I'm saying and
说第一，人民。
saying number one, The People.
那么公司最大的问题之一就是他们的
Then one of the biggest problems that companies have is that their
代码基是可怕的，它们充满了croft与调用遗产它是
code bases are awful, that they're full of croft there with the call legacy it's
只是糟糕的东西，这严重损害了公司的竞争能力。
just awful stuff and that seriously impairs the company's ability to compete.
你不能改变，你不能扩展，你不能成长
That you can't make changes, you can't extend, you can't grow
因为软件质量差，所以阻碍了你的发展。
because the software is holding you back because of it's poor quality.
软件变成了负债而不是资产。
The software becomes a liability rather than an asset.
我认为我们可以改变这一点，如果我们正在编写高质量的软件
And I think we can change that if we're writing high quality of software for
团队，我们让公司变得更有竞争力，
the team, that we allow the company then to be much more competitive,
更具响应性，更好地服务于市场。
much more responsive, much better to serve the market.
假设您正在编写自己的软件，
Suppose you're writing your own software,
你的家，你在做你自己的事情，那么你的责任是什么？
your home and you're doing your own stuff, what are your responsibilities then?
头号人物仍然是人们，假设其他人将不得不
Number one still The People, assuming that someone else is ever gonna have to
写你的东西你真的应该为他们写好无论他们是谁，
write your stuff you really should write it well for them whoever they might be,
即使你不知道他们会是谁，当你知道他们会是谁的时候，心里还是应该有一个人
even if you don't know who they're gonna be should still have somebody in mind when
你在写这些东西。
you're writing this stuff.
然后是球队的第二名，如果你有任何野心的话
And then number two The Team, if you have any ambition of
这个东西变得足够好，你可能会想要开放它的源代码
this stuff getting good enough that you might wanna open source it that
意味着您的团队现在可能是世界上的每个程序员。
means your team is now potentially every programmer in the world.
所以让它对他们有好处。
So make it good for them.
然后第三位是你的管理层所以请自便。
And then number three your management so knock yourself out.
这就是我们的结局。
That brings us to the end.
我想不出还有什么可以告诉你的。
I can't think of anything else to tell you.
所以，非常感谢大家。
So, thank you all very much.
但在我们走之前，我有一个建议。
But before we go, I've got one piece of advice.
这真的很严重，我希望你不要忘记这一点。
This is really serious, I hope you don't forget this.
这是，我现在是认真的。
This is, I'm really serious now.
请不要制造虫子。
Please, don't make bugs.
&gt；&gt；扬声器2：[笑]&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：谢谢。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: [LAUGH] &gt;&gt; Douglas: Thank you.
&gt；&gt；[掌声]&gt；&gt；扬声器2：我们已经
&gt;&gt; [APPLAUSE] &gt;&gt; Speaker 2: We've
查德随机问了几个问题。
got a couple random questions from Chad.
我不确定你是否还想回答更多的问题。
I'm not sure if you want to take any more questions but.
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：它们好吗？
&gt;&gt; Douglas: Are they good?
&GT；&GT；演讲者2：嗯，这只是一种关于SWIFT的意见，意见。
&gt;&gt; Speaker 2: Well it's just kind of opinions, opinions on Swift.
我对斯威夫特没有意见。
I don't have an opinion on Swift.
[相声]&gt；&gt；演讲者3：你的意见如何
[CROSSTALK] &gt;&gt; Speaker 3: How about your opinion
打字稿？
on typescript?
&gt；&gt；道格拉斯：在打字稿上，我认为打字稿是一个陷阱，它把你困在里面
&gt;&gt; Douglas: On typescript, I see typescript as a trap, it keeps you in
一个经典的模型，如果你的函数被锁定在打字稿中，你永远也找不出函数。
a classical model, you'll never figure out functions if yours locked into typescript.